# **Chentao Yang**

Dr. of astrophysics













Total citations: 1046 H-index: 19

As a trained **astrophysicist**, I have a solid foundation in **math** and **physics**. My 10+ years experience in observational astrophysics research has sharpened my data analysis skills and scientific exploration spirits. I'm **curious** and versed in dissecting complex problems, while maintaining the balance intricate details with big-picture perspectives.

#### **TOOLSET**











Shell (Unix/Linux), Julia, FORTRAN, Lang: IDL, Python (NumPy, Pandas, Astropy, Matplotlib, ...), Matlab, Mathematica

VS Code, Jupyter Lab, Git, Late, LyX, S/W: Obsidian, Adobe Illustrator, FontLab MS Office (Excel, PowerPoint)...

#### **LANGUAGE**

English Full proficiency
Mandarin Native
French Elementary

Swedish Beginner Spanish Beginner

#### **INTERESTS**



Philosophy, Fiction, Science



D<sup>⊯</sup> Jazz, Classic, Soundtrack



Hiking, Citywalk



🕽 Sci-fi, Indie, Mystery

## **QUICK FACTS**

- 50+ pulications in top international journals,
   1000+ citations, several press releases
- **5+ GitHub projects**, **50+ stars** (using programming, Bayesian/frequentist statistics, MCMC, graphic design)
- **12+ Oral presentations** in prestigious international conferences (including invited)
- 500+ award PI observing telescope time from 30+ proposals.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Postdoctral Researcher in astrophysics (2021-current)

Chalmers tekniska högskola

- Analyzed large interferometric radio data sets of galaxies.
- Creative visualization of astronomical images and related physical parameters.
- Quantified data and interpreted results via mathematical & physical models.
- Leadership in international team for independent complete research projects.

## Postdoctral Research Fellow in astrophysics (2017-2021)

European Southern Observatory (ESO)/Joint ALMA Observatory

- Prestigious fellowship in the leading astronomical research center, ESO (Chile).
- Hands-on with the most advanced ground-based observatory, ALMA.
- Independent research from ideas to publications.
- Leading international collaborations.

## **EDUCATION**

#### PhD in Astrophysics (dual-diploma)

Université Paris-Saclay (2014-2017)

(Top 20 in Academic Ranking of World Universities)

University of Chinese Academy of Sciences (2013-2017)

(Top 70 in Academic Ranking of World Universities)

#### **Master in Astrophysics**

Beijing Normal Univesity (2010-2013)

## **Bachelor in Astronomy**

Beijing Normal University (2006-2010)

(Graduate with distinguished honour, in both university and city levels)

## **SKILLS**

Team work, Effective communication, Project management, Programming, Creative data visualization, Data intuition, Problem-sovling, Critical thinking, Curiosity

## **AWARDS**

#### Several Scholarships and Funding Awards

- NAOC (National Astronomical Observatory of China) Scholarship
- National Undergraduate Innovative Test Program Grant (10k CNY)
- ESO Science Support Discretionary Fund (9k EUR)
- The LIA-Origins Short Visit Program Grant (3k EUR)

#### **Fellowship**

ESO Fellowship (Chile), 4-year independent research funding